A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10052107), 2000 September 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R8788)
    United States; Arts and society -- United States; Performing Arts--Social aspects--United States; Feminism and the arts; Art and race -- United States
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10100550), 2001 June 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9133)
    Support to build a network in Indonesia and the U.S. of scholars of history, anthropology, cultural studies, and post-colonial studies
    Indonesia (Jakarta); Education, Sexuality, Religion
    $97,500.00; $97,500.00
    Arbuckle, Heidi L.; Volkman, Toby Alice
    Indonesia; United States; Student exchange programs--United States; Education, Higher -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc. -- United States; Student exchange programs--Indonesia; Education, Higher -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc. -- Indonesia
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10101407), 2001 August 01-2004 July 31 (Reel R9124)
    For the university's Center for South Asian Studies to establish a network on South Asian politics and political economy for younger scholars at U.S., European and South Asian academic institutions
    $180,000.00; $176,103.22
    South Asia; Political science--Study and teaching
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10150625), 2000 September 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R8847)
    Support for research and public policy development on "Globalization, Tax Competition, and the Social Insurance Crisis"
    $50,902.03; $50,753.26
    Global; Globalization -- Research; Taxation--Research; International coOperation -- Research; International economic relations
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10200955), 2002 June 01-2004 December 31 (Reel R9164)
    For the newly instituted environmental justice initiative at the School of Natural Resources and the Environment
    Miller-Travis, Vernice; DePass, Michelle
    United States; Environmental law --Study and teaching
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10250401), 2002 January 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9035)
    To design a comparative survey research project on inequality in collaboration with research centers in large metropolitan areas in five countries
    $45,500.00; $45,500.00
    Global; Social sciences--Research; Civil society -- Global -- Research
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10300349), 2003 January 01-2005 December 31 (Reel R9121)
    For research on the impact of inter-ethnic networks of civic engagement on incidence of conflict
    Governance and Civil Society; India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi); West Africa (Lagos)
    Edwards, Michael; Raman, Sushma; TBS/PSJ
    Sri Lanka; Indonesia; Malaysia; Nigeria
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10351210), 2003 May 01-2004 September 30 (Reel R9128)
    For a meeting of university presidents, corporate & civil rights leaders & activists immediately following the Supreme Court's decisions on affirmative action and for public education outreach work
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10351377), 2004 January 01-2004 December 31 (Reel R9089)
    For the Program on Poverty and Social Welfare Policy to add a qualitative research component on how participation in the low-wage labor market impacts women's lives
    Economic Development; Assets - Office of the Vice President
    Neuborne, Helen; Campbell, Elizabeth C.
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10351772), 2003 October 01-2004 September 30 (Reel R9149)
    To share lessons and strategies to promote affirmative action in higher education
    Fraser, Gertrude Jacinta
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10351849), 2003 October 01-2004 September 30 (Reel R9084)
    For collaborative research on the causes and consequences of continued residential segregation by race and economic class in Detroit and Chicago
    $100,000.00; $99,943.87
    Illinois; Michigan
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10450454), 2004 January 01-2004 December 31 (Reel R9191)
    To plan a new Center for Institutional Diversity
  - Regents of the University of Wisconsin (09901149), 1999 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8884)
    Partial support for the urban network to improve teacher education
    United States; Teachers--Training of--United States; Educational change -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States
  - Regents of the University of Wisconsin (10100410), 2000 November 01-2002 October 31 (Reel R8800)
    Support for conceptualization and development of a model for a noncommercial public space on the Internet
    United States; Internetworking (Telecommunication); Telecommunication policy--United States; Information Technology--Social aspects
  - Regents of the University of Wisconsin (10101177), 2001 June 20-2004 June 19 (Reel R9115)
    For applied research, capacity building and community activism on the role of assets in mitigating livelihood risk among the urban poor in Lucknow
    $296,830.00; $296,830.00
    India; Development economics -- India; Community development -- India
  - Regents of the University of Wisconsin (10101778), 2001 July 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9090)
    For culturally competent capacity-building assistance to foundation-supported, Asian-American women-led, community-based organizations that program in reproductive health
  - Regents of the University of Wisconsin (10350250), 2003 January 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9133)
    For Media Policy Education: The Gap between Curriculum and Need, a project to improve the education of future policymakers by helping universities better design media policy curricula
  - Regional Academy For Rural Development (07650215), 1975 October 01-1977 July 31 (Reel R1228, Reel R5333)
    Purchase of books and journals, equipment and transport
    $15,000.00; $14,994.55
    Fuller, William P.
  - Regional Center for Adult Education in Latin America and the Caribbean (10250140), 2001 October 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8981)
    For a Latin American workshop on the production of adult education materials and to publish the workshop report
  - Regional Center for Socio Economic Studies (08450322), 1984 January 03-1984 July 02 (Reel R3694, Reel R4427)
    Support for a seminar on culture and violence in peru
    $2,700.00; $2,700.00
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (09301221), 1993 September 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R8032)
    Support for a new center to encourage research and networking on regional security issues in south asia
    International Affairs Program [IA]; India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi); Asia & The Pacific [ASIA]
    $488,000.00; $488,000.00
    Geithner, Peter F.; George, Terrence R.; Wing, Christine B.
    India; South Asia
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (09701073), 1997 August 01-2001 July 31 (Reel R8723)
    Support for a south asian research network on regional security and international relations
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (09801809), 1998 September 28-1999 September 27 (Reel R7855)
    Support for the development of an asia regionwide security and cooperation research program
    Asia; Peace--Asia--Research
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (09901741), 1999 September 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R8875)
    Support for broadening and deepening the security discourse in asia to include non-traditional security concerns
    India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi); Indonesia (Jakarta); Philippines (Manila); Vietnam and Thailand (Hanoi); China (Beijing)
    $410,000.00; $410,000.00
    Asia; Peace--Research; National Security (Law)--Asia
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (10051063), 2000 June 01-2001 May 31 (Reel R8693)
    Support to conduct an external review and evaluation of the work of the regional centre for srategic studies since its inception
    $31,500.00; $31,500.00
    Asia; Security (Law), International; Peace--Research
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (10051954), 2000 October 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R8892)
    Interim support for core staff salaries and the kodikara awards program
    Asia; Peace--Research; International cooperation; Security (Law), International; Foreign study--AWards--Asia
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (10101702), 2001 August 01-2002 July 31 (Reel R8946)
    For core support and to continue the Kodikara Awards Program, conduct research and organize a workshop for directors of South Asian institutes of strategic and security studies
    South Asia; Security (Law), International; Peace--Research
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (10251965), 2002 September 15-2003 September 14 (Reel R9203)
    For research awards, networking and publications in strategic, regional security and other international issues relating to South Asia
  - Regional Center for Strategic Studies (10300597), 2003 March 01-2004 August 31 (Reel R9237)
    For collaborative research project on understanding and combating terrorism in South Asia
    India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi); China (Beijing); Indonesia (Jakarta); Philippines (Manila); Vietnam and Thailand (Hanoi)
    Lawry, Steven W.; Watson, Andrew; Siskel, Suzanne E.; Bailey, Charles R.
  - Regional Center for Third World Studies (08950552), 1989 May 01-1990 August 01 (Reel R6326, Reel R6452)
    Policy-oriented research on world oil markets and politics relevant to colombia
  - Regional Charitable Organization for Aid to Refugees and Forced Migrants "Civic Assistance" (10050258), 1999 November 01-2000 March 31 (Reel R8475)
    Support for a humanitarian assistance organization working with refugees from chechnya in moscow and ingushetiia
    Russia; Human rights advocacy -- Russia (Federation); Human rights -- Russia (Federation) -- Chechnya
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10152027), 2001 September 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R8967)
    To review and assess its policy in Indonesia in order to develop a collaborative program with local institutions
    Indonesia; Forests and forestry -- Indonesia; Community forests -- Indonesia -- Management
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10152065), 2001 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R9239)
    For training and other assistance to community forestry projects in Southwest China
    China; Community forests -- China; Forests and forestry -- China
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10201024), 2002 July 01-2004 December 31 (Reel R9115)
    To promote community forestry in Asia in the context of the World Summit for Sustainable Development
    China; Forests and forestry -- Asia; Community forests -- Asia
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10201242), 2002 April 01-2004 September 30 (Reel R9098)
    General support to develop and implement mechanisms for identifying, enhancing and sharing practices and ideas for promoting community forestry on a regional basis
    India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi); Indonesia (Jakarta); Vietnam and Thailand (Hanoi); China (Beijing); Community and Resource Development
    $810,000.00; $810,000.00
    Belbase, Narayan; Capistrano, Ana Doris; Pradhan, Ujjwal; Bailey, Charles R.; Mallee, Henricus P.; Duncan, Cynthia M.
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10351527), 2003 July 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9229)
    For training, technical assistance and other activities to facilitate community forestry and forest governance in southwest China
    $149,400.00; $149,400.00
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10400365), 2004 March 01-2005 October 31 (Reel R9239)
    $238,800.00; $233,682.07
  - Regional Community Forestry Training Center for Asia and the Pacific (RECOFTC) (10451009), 2004 July 01-2005 June 30 (Reel R9153)
    For collaborative work with grantees, partners and program officers in Indonesia, South Africa and Kenya to further learning about and application of payments for environmental services with equity
    Mexico and Central America (Mexico City); Indonesia (Jakarta); Southern Africa (Johannesburg); Eastern Africa (Nairobi)
    Barry, Deborah; Pradhan, Ujjwal; Nimpuno-Parente, Paula; Nuvunga, Milagre
    Indonesia; Africa, East; Africa, Southern; Global
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (08400906), 1984 September 15-1987 April 30 (Reel R5325, Reel R5720)
    Support for research on the sources of crisis in central america and on alternative solutions
    Cox, Stephen B.
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (08851040), 1988 May 01-1990 June 30 (Reel R5803, Reel R6069)
    Support for a network of social science research centers in central america
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (09551146), 1995 August 01-1996 July 31 (Reel R7200)
    Support for the reorganization and upgrading of the nicarao electronic communications network in central america
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (09901391), 1999 July 01-2003 January 31 (Reel R9026)
    Support for policy research on the relationship between citizen security, democratic governance, and sustainable development in the seven central american countries
    Mexico and Central America (Mexico City); PSJ - Office of the Vice President; Human Rights
    Brown, Kimberli R.; Eguizabal, Cristina
    Central America; Social Justice--Central America; Sustainable development--Central America; Civil society -- Central America
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (10001228), 2000 June 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8854)
    Support to establish a regional coordinating program in cuba to promote intellectual exchange between cuba and the greater carribean basin
    Cuba; International relations; Social sciences--Cuba; Social sciences--Caribbean Area; Exchange of persons programs
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (10350297), 2003 January 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9173)
    To develop a program of academic exchanges and activities in the Greater Caribbean
    Cuba; West Indies
  - Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research (10550176), 2004 November 01-2005 October 31 (Reel R9179)
    Cuba; Central America; West Indies
  - Regional Council For Education (07350579), 1973 April 09-1973 September 08 (Reel R1219)
    Expenses for twelve participants in workshop on curriculum innovation, january 1973
    $9,158.00; $9,158.00
  - Regional Council For International Education (06400167), 1964 February 05-1970 February 05 (Reel R2073)
    Summer orientation center for foreign students
  - Regional Council For International Education (06400204), 1964 March 09-1968 March 08 (Reel R1281)
    Cooperative faculty development program in international studies
  - Regional Council on Human Rights in Asia (08750079), 1986 September 01-1987 December 31 (Reel R5383, Reel R5727)
    Support for travel costs for attendees at rchra's fourth general assembly in manila
  - Regional Information and Support Centre for Ngos (10002017), 2000 October 01-2002 September 30 (Reel R8962)
    Program support for the development and enlargement of a support center serving a network of six major polish nongovernmental organizations
    Europe, Eastern; Non-governmental organizations--Poland
  - Regional Institute of Higher Education and Development (Rihed) (07400320), 1970 July 30-1976 July 29 (Reel R1994, Reel R3240, Reel R3603)
    Support of research and development of higher education in southeast asia
    Frodin, Reuben; Pfanner, David E.
  - Regional Institute of Higher Education and Development (Rihed) (07750177), 1977 February 01-1977 June 01 (Reel R1225, Reel R3741)
    Support for an interview of candidates for the posts of director and deputy director of rihed
    $1,714.00; $1,702.80
  - Regional Institute of Higher Education and Development (Rihed) (08250566), 1982 March 01-1982 April 30 (Reel R3545, Reel R5052)
    Partial support of a workshop on the "sociology of development" to be held in singapore in march 1982
  - Regional Institute of Higher Education and Development (Rihed) (08350711), 1983 May 15-1983 November 14 (Reel R3702, Reel R5104)
    Support for a workshop on university and policy research in southeast asia
    $7,592.00; $7,116.00
  - Regional Open Social Institute (09950651), 1999 April 01-2001 July 31 (Reel R8645)
    To support legal clinics in two russian cities
    Russia; Legal services--Russia (Federation); Legal aid--Russia (Federation)
  - Regional Plan Association (05600210), 1956 July 18-1959 September 24 (Reel R0156)
    Study of new york metropolitan region
  - Regional Plan Association (05700248), 1957 June 18-1958 June 17 (Reel R0166)
    Reappraisal of techniques and organization of regional planning (study)
  - Regional Plan Association (06000323), 1960 August 04-1963 August 03 (Reel R0158)
    Follow up its study of metropolitan new york and strengthen non-governmental leadership
  - Regional Plan Association (06200103), 1961 December 26-1964 December 31 (Reel R0392)
    Distribution abroad of new york metropolitan region study
  - Regional Plan Association (06400234), 1964 April 06-1968 July 06 (Reel R2128, Reel R2129)
    Preparation of a comprehensive development plan for the new york metropolitan region
  - Regional Plan Association (07000044), 1969 October 30-1970 October 29 (Reel R1687)
    Preparation of a region-wide development plan for the seven-county mid-hudson region
    Mavity, Jane H.
  - Regional Plan Association (07000479), 1970 July 23-1974 June 30 (Reel R1068)
    Conferences to promote citizen involvement in regional planning
  - Regional Plan Association (07100377), 1971 June 01-1975 September 30 (Reel R1127, Reel R3829)
    Analyses of 1970 census data for the new york metropolitan region
    $252,600.00; $252,600.00
  - Regional Plan Association (07300133), 1973 January 16-1974 August 12 (Reel R1067)
    Evaluation of program to mobilize citizen participation in series of televised "town meetings" on regional basis
  - Regional Plan Association (07500077), 1974 October 01-1975 September 30 (Reel R1460)
    Partial support to prepare a manual on land use and public transportation planning
  - Regional Plan Association (07600092), 1975 December 01-1979 June 30 (Reel R2896)
    Support for editing and publication of report on housing policy development in new york region
    $33,500.00; $33,500.00
  - Regional Plan Association (07700624), 1977 October 01-1978 November 30 (Reel R2976)
    Part. Support for a study of the implications for land use policy of energy consumption and emissions assoc. With automobile travel
  - Regional Plan Association (08050150), 1979 December 01-1981 March 31 (Reel R3066)
    Partial support of a study of travel requirements of alternative office building settings
  - Regional Plan Association (08050307), 1980 January 15-1980 December 31 (Reel R2703)
    Partial support for a slide show on the subject of the south bronx
    $11,060.00; $11,060.00
  - Regional Plan Association (08100174), 1981 January 01-1981 April 30 (Reel R2905, Reel R2906)
    Support for the production of a documentary film on the subject of the south bronx
    $4,000.00; $251.00
  - Regional Plan Association (08750412), 1986 October 01-1987 September 30 (Reel R5749)
    Partial support for preparation of research papers for the first world congress of the world association of the major metropolises
    New York (N.Y.); Global
  - Regional Plan Association (10000894), 2000 April 01-2005 March 31 (Reel R9164)
    Support for a project to develop a community strategic plan to respond and capitalize on opportunities created by a new subway corridor to be built in a low-income community in new york city
    New York (N.Y.); Connecticut; New Jersey; New York (State); Community development -- New York (State) -- New York (State)
  - Regional Plan Association (10200999), 2002 April 01-2005 March 31 (Reel R9186)
    For the Civic Alliance Project to develop strategies for the rebuilding of Lower Manhattan in the wake of the September 11 attack on the World Trade Center
    Anthony, Carl; Campbell, Elizabeth C.; Farias Campero, Pablo
    New York (N.Y.); Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Community development -- United States; Sustainable development--United States; Economic development
  - Regional Population Center (07300416), 1973 May 02-1979 December 31 (Reel R2481, Reel R3202, Reel R3337, Reel R3338)
    Support for the center's research and training programs in population
    $517,000.00; $517,000.00
  - Regional Population Center (07400614), 1974 September 24-1980 September 30 (Reel R3091, Reel R0092, Reel R3526, Reel R0027, Reel R4102)
    Support of the latin american program of research in human reproduction (plamirh)
    Latin America & The Caribbean [LAC]; Population [POP]
    Harkavy, Oscar; Puryear, Jeffrey
  - Regional Population Center (07450092), 1973 December 02-1974 March 01 (Reel R1227, Reel R3267)
    Support for a colombian venezuelan workshop in family life and sexeducation to be held in cucuta, december 2-5, 1973
    $4,103.00; $4,103.00
  - Regional Population Center (08050853), 1980 July 07-1983 December 31 (Reel R3694, Reel R3828)
    Support for a study of education and unemployment
    $36,000.00; $30,000.00
  - Regional Population Center (09850857), 1998 April 01-1999 December 31 (Reel R8375)
    Support for research on philanthropies and social change in colombia
    $84,200.00; $84,200.00
    Colombia; Humanitarianism--Colombia
  - Regional Program On Employment For Latin America And The Caribbean (07450675), 1974 September 01-1974 November 30 (Reel R1997)
    Support for a workshop on employment problems in latin america
  - Regional Program On Employment For Latin America And The Caribbean (07600136), 1976 February 25-1982 December 31 (Reel R4050, Reel R3719, Reel R3720, Reel R5202)
    Strengthening multidisciplinary research on employment
  - Regional Program On Employment For Latin America And The Caribbean (07750398), 1977 June 06-1977 September 05 (Reel R2863, Reel R3183)
    Partial support for a seminar on employment problems in latin america
    $3,960.00; $3,727.00
  - Regional Program on Employment for Latin America and the Caribbean (09250663), 1992 March 01-1993 December 31 (Reel R7079)
    Research on micro-enterprise credit programs in 4 latin american countries
    $69,250.00; $69,250.00
  - Regional Public Charitable Foundation for Seriously Ill and Needy Children (10050270), 2000 January 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R9013)
    Support to systematize and strengthen an exploratory effort to use interactive internet technology to increase charitable donations and private philanthopy in russia
    $41,000.00; $41,000.00
    Russia; Humanitarianism--Russia (Federation); Internetworking (Telecommunication)
  - Regional Public Charitable Foundation for Seriously Ill and Needy Children (10351453), 2003 August 01-2004 July 31 (Reel R9178)
    To organize circus visits and artists performances for patients of the Russian Children's Clinical Hospital in Moscow
  - Regional Research Institute on Andean Ecology (08450302), 1984 February 28-1984 August 27 (Reel R4083, Reel R4827)
    Support for a conference assessing rural development experiences of intermediate support groups in the peruvian highlands
  - Regional Secretariat For Africa And Madagascar (06400296), 1964 June 08-1965 June 07 (Reel R0930)
    First panafrican conference on catholic education
  - Regional Society of the Disabled "Perspektiva" (10000470), 2000 February 01-2003 March 31 (Reel R9013)
    Support to test and extend a model of community service that integrates disabled with able-bodied youth, and attracts volunteers for tasks to promote equal access in three russian cities
    $329,000.00; $329,000.00